lot18.com 2017-06-14

# Privacy Policy | Lot18

This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") explains our policy regarding the collection, use, disclosure and transfer of your information by L18 Holdings, Inc., its affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively "Lot18"). By “information” we mean information you provide to us that personally identifies you ("Personal Information") as well as general, non-personal information that is automatically collected from our site ("Non-Personal Information"). Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. If you do not agree to our practices, please do not register, subscribe, create an account, or otherwise interact with Lot18 at www.lot18.com (the "Website"). By visiting the Website, you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

## Information Collection

Lot18 collects Personal Information to customize the content and/or layout of the Website for each member and to contact members regarding their accounts. We collect information you provide to us when you begin the process of placing an order through the Website (even when you abandon the transaction). If a member chooses to place an order through the Website, we collect additional information including, but not limited to, the member's billing address, shipping address, date of birth, date of order, and product ordered ("Transaction Information"). 

Lot18 also collects Non-Personal Information or general statistics about each user that visits the Lot18 Website. Non-Personal Information is collected and recorded to understand statistics and usage of the Lot18 Website. Non-Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, a user’s ISP (Internet Service Provider), IP (Internet Protocol) address, the type of web browser used, which pages a user visits, and other site usage data. This information is completely anonymous and used to analyze Lot18's Website traffic and other statistics relating to the usage of its Website. 

## Use and Disclosure of Information, and Opt-Out Procedure

Lot18 may disclose Personal Information if it is required to do so by law or if disclosing Personal Information is vital to identify, contact, or bring legal action in order to protect Lot18, its customers, or third parties. In addition, Personal Information that you provide to us (such as your name, address and email address) may be combined with other personally identifiable information (such as demographic information and past Transaction Information) available from our records and other sources. This information will be used to make our future marketing efforts more efficient. This information may also be shared with our third party service providers that assist us with our marketing efforts and with other marketers whose products or services we feel may be of interest to you. If you prefer that we do not share your personally identifiable information with other marketers, please email us at [[optout@lot18.com](mailto:optout@lot18.com)]. In the event that you choose to opt out as set forth above, please note that the following three paragraphs will still apply: 

Transaction Information will be shared with the merchant from whom the purchase is made, and may be provided to other trusted third parties as necessary to process and fulfill the order, and to help enable Lot 18 to provide better member services and offerings. All such merchants and third parties are contractually obligated to keep all Transaction Information confidential, maintain the privacy of all Lot18 members, and to use such Transaction Information only to provide services to Lot 18 for the benefit of Lot 18 and its members. Transaction Information may also be used to develop a personalized profile and shopping history for each member in order to customize promotions, updates or special offers. 

From time to time, we may employ other companies and individuals to perform services, to maintain and operate the Website, and to maintain certain features on the Website. To such parties, we may disclose Non-Personal Information such as traffic patterns and Website usage data, but such information will not include Personal Information. We also may employ reputable third parties to analyze our sales data for internal analysis, during which we may disclose Personal Information such as the wines purchased, the location of shipment, and the frequency of purchases. 

We additionally may enlist a third party to assist with marketing and sending member e-mails; in this case, we will provide these third party vendors only with member e-mail addresses. These third parties will not receive or be given access to other Personal Information (such as Lot18 member home addresses, phone numbers, or date of birth) unless Lot18 is required to do so by law or unless disclosing such Personal Information is vital to identify, contact, or bring legal action in order to protect Lot18, its customers, or third parties. 

## Cookies and Web Beacons

When you visit the Website, our service providers may place cookies on your computers or mobile devices. A cookie is a small amount of information that a web server sends to your browser that stores information about your account, preferences and use of the Website. Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return and track and target your interests in order to provide a customized experience. They also help us to detect certain kinds of fraud. We use cookies to store a member's preferences, record session information, record member-specific information on what pages are accessed or visited, alert members to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to our Website, or customize web page content based on browser type or other information that the member sends. 

"Session" cookies are temporary cookies used for various reasons, such as managing page views and your shopping cart. Typically, your browser will erase session cookies once you exit the browser. "Persistent" cookies are more permanent cookies that are stored on your computer or mobile device after you exit the browser. Persistent cookies allow us to retrieve certain information that you have previously provided to us (for example, your user ID if you ask to be remembered). The Lot18 Website uses both session and persistent cookies. 

We also use web beacons. Web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on website pages or in our e-mails that allow us to determine whether you have performed certain actions. When you access these pages or open e-mail messages, the web beacons generate a notice of that action to us, or our service providers. These tools allow us to measure response to our communications and improve our web pages and promotions. 

You may manage how your browser handles cookies and related technologies by adjusting your browser's security and privacy settings. Refer to instructions related to your browser to learn about privacy and security settings that are available to you. If you block or delete cookies, you may not be able to use particular features of the Lot18 Website or may not be able to use the Website in its full capacity. 

## Referring Friends to Lot18

We enable you to refer friends to Lot18. You may be eligible to receive referral credit if someone that you refer to Lot18 makes a purchase (see Terms and Conditions for details). If you wish to refer friends, we provide you a unique referral link that you can share directly with others via message from Lot18, e-mail, social media websites, or other communication methods. If someone clicks your link and takes a qualifying action, we may attribute that referral to you for purposes such as awarding you referral credit. We do not collect any Personal or Non-Personal Information about the persons with whom you share your link until the persons click the link and engage directly with Lot18. If a person clicks the link, the Lot18 website automatically collects Non-Personal Information, which may include the person's IP address, ISP, and other Non-Personal Information. Personal Information is only collected if the person chooses to sign up and become a member of Lot18, or otherwise engages directly with Lot18. 

## Privacy Practices of Third Parties

Our Website may contain links to third party websites, products, and services. These websites may include but are not limited to wineries, gourmet food websites, travel websites, or social media websites such as Facebook and Twitter. Information collected by these third party websites is governed by their privacy practices and is not subject to this privacy policy. We are not responsible for how these third party websites collect, use, disclose, distribute, or maintain Personal and Non-Personal Information. If you visit a third party website listed on the Lot18 Website, you do so at your own risk. We encourage you to learn about the privacy practices of those third parties prior to providing them with an information or taking advantage of an offer or promotion. 

## Lot18 Blog Content

We are not responsible for protecting any Personal Information that you post on our blog or on social media web pages associated with Lot18. Although we reserve the right to monitor any postings, all Personal Information that is posted on these websites is unprotected and can be seen by anyone with access to the specific website. 

## Protection of Your Information

We take many precautions to safeguard your Personal Information, Non-Personal Information, and Transaction Information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. In addition to administrative and physical protective measures, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where Personal information is collected. For this reason, in order to complete a protected transaction, you must use a SSL-enabled browser to access the Website. Safari, Firefox, and Internet Explorer are all SSL-enabled. Using these types of browsers protects the confidentiality of your Personal Information while it is being transferred over the Internet. 

We store credit card numbers in a third-party, one-way vault. When we interact directly with a credit card company, the card number is encrypted and only lives on the Website for a few seconds before it is transferred into the secure vault. 

When creating an account on our Website, you are required to establish a password. To maximize your level of protection, you should choose a password with at least 6 characters, using a combination of letters and numbers. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and account information. 

While Lot18 uses standard security procedures and practices relative to safeguarding your Information, no Internet data transaction can be guaranteed as 100% secure. Consequently, while Lot18 strives to protect and conserve your Information, we do not guarantee or attest comprehensive security of your Information transmission. If you transmit Information to Lot18, you do so at your own risk. 

## Collection of Information from Minors

We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from minors under 21, nor do we direct any of our content to minors under 21. If we learn that we collected the Personal Information of a minor, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible. 

## Accessing and Correcting Personal Information

You can access, update and delete your Personal Information by logging into your account and accessing the "My Account" section of the Website. If you want to close your account or have questions, please contact us at [service@lot18.com](mailto:service@lot18.com). While we are ready to assist you in managing your subscriptions, closing your account, and removing your active member profile, we cannot always delete all records. For example, we are required to retain records relating to previous transactions on the Website for financial reporting and compliance reasons. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as necessary to provide you services and to maintain a record of your transactions for financial reporting and compliance purposes. If you wish to cancel your account, please contact us at [service@lot18.com](mailto:service@lot18.com). We will retain and use your Personal Information, Non-Personal Information, and Transaction Information only as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements, and otherwise as permitted by law. 

## E-mail Opt Out

Registered members who have elected to receive Lot18's daily e-mail can choose to opt-out at any time by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any daily e-mail. In addition, members may unsubscribe by contacting Lot18 Member Services at (855) 695-6818. Further questions or comments regarding privacy can be directed to [privacy@lot18.com](mailto:privacy@lot18.com). 

## California Privacy Rights

Pursuant to SS1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information about the types of Personal Information that companies with whom they have an established business relationship have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. In particular, the law provides that companies must inform consumers about the categories of Personal Information that have been shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the types of services or products marketed by those third parties. To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Lot18 pursuant to the above references provision, please contact us via email at [service@lot18.com](mailto:service@lot18.com). 

## Changes to Privacy Policy

From time to time, Lot18 will, in its own discretion, update its privacy policy with or without prior notice. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check our Website periodically. Your continued use of the Lot18 Website amounts to your agreement to comply with and obey the terms of our most recent Privacy Policy. If you object to any of the terms, you should cease to use the Lot18 Website. 

## Contact Information

If you, at any point in time, have any questions or concerns with respect to the Lot18 Privacy Policy, you can e-mail us at [privacy@lot18.com](mailto:privacy@lot18.com).   
2 Clark Place   
Mahopac, NY 10541
